蜘蛛侠
我是谁  你真的想知道
Who am I?You sure you want to know?
胆小鬼千万别听我的故事
The story of my life is not for the faint of heart.
如果有人说这是个喜剧
If somebody said it was a happy little tale...
而我也只是个平凡且无忧无虑的普通人
...if somebody told you I was just an average guy,not a care in the world...
那你就被骗了
...somebody lied.
但我向你保证  这就跟其它的精彩故事一样
But let me assure you,this,like any story worth telling...
全是为了一个女孩
...is all about a girl.
就是她  邻家的女孩  玛莉珍华森
That girl.The girl next door.Mary Jane Watson.
我从小就爱她
The woman I've loved since before I liked girls.
我很想说  坐在她身边的那个人就是我
I'd like to tell you that's me next to her.
唉  能当他也不错
Aw,heck,I'd even take him.
喂  停车
Hey!Stop the bus!
那是我
That's me.
拜托你  叫他停车
Tell him to stop!Please!
停车
Stop!
喂  停车
Hey!Stop the bus!
快停车  他一路在追我们
Stop!He's been chasing us since Woodhaven.
去叫计程车啦  派克
Catch a cab,Parker!
谢了  抱歉我迟到了
Thank you.I'm sorry I'm late.
他真笨啊
What a geek!
-你想都别想  -你真差劲  派克
- Don't even think about it. - You're so lame,Parker.
你会跟他约会吗
Would you date him?
市公立高三生
Midtown High seniors.
别乱跑  直走到  别闹了
No wandering.Proceed direct--Knock it off.
记住  这是个难得的机会
Remember,it is a privilege to be here.
我们是哥伦比亚大学科学院的客人
We're guests of Columbia University's Science Department.
大家乖乖守规矩
So behave accordingly.
别像上次在天文馆一样给我桶篓子
Let's not have a repeat of our trip to the planetarium.
同学们  别走散了
Come on,stay together.
大家一起走进去
Proceed up the steps and into the building.
-你去哪了  -去看图书馆
- Where were you? - Checking out the library.
-去看书啊  -是啊  真的啊
- Looking at the books. - Yeah,right.
-我们可以绕到角落去吗  -为什么
- Can we drive around the corner? - Why?
入口就在这里
The entrance is right there.
爸爸  公立高中生不太好坐劳斯莱斯到啦
Dad,this is public school.I can't show up in a Rolls.
就因为你被私立中学退学
I should trade my car for a Jetta...
我就该换辆福士金龟车吗
...because you flunked out of private school?
-那不合我  -这当然合你
- It wasn't for me. - Of course it was.
-千万别以自己为耻  -我才没有
- Don't ever be ashamed of who you are. - I'm not ashamed of who I am.
只是
It's just....
只是什么  哈利
Just what,Harry?
算了
Forget it.
彼得
Pete!
-嗨  哈利  -嗨  你好吗
- Hi,Harry. - Hey,man.What's up?
-你不带背包吗  -谢了
- Won't you be needing this? - Thanks.
-这是我爸爸  奥诺曼  -我常听到你的大名
- This is my father,Norman Osborn. - I've heard so much about you.
-很荣幸认识您  -哈利说你对科学颇有研究
- It's an honor,sir. - Harry says you're a science whiz.
我也算是科学家
I'm something of a scientist myself.
我拜读过您那有关纳米的科研报告  真的很棒
I read your research on nanotechnology.Brilliant.
-你看得懂吗  -是的  我还写了份报告
- You understood it? - Yes,I wrote a paper on it.
真令人钦佩  你爸妈一定以你这天才为傲
Impressive.Your parents must be very proud.
-我和叔叔婶婶住  -你们两个  我们走吧
- I live with my aunt and uncle. - Hey,you two!Let's move!
-幸会了  -希望能再见面
- Nice to meet you. - Hope to see you again.
-你爸爸人很好  -只因你是个天才
- He doesn't seem so bad. - Not if you're a genius.
我看他很想领养你
I think he wants to adopt you.
世上有三万两千多种蜘蛛
There are over 32,000 known species of spider in the world.
蜘蛛目之下分为三大类
They're in the order Araneae,divided into three suborders.
好棒啊
That's amazing!
这是西岸最先进的电子显微镜
This is the most advanced electron microscope on the East Coast.
真不敢相信
It's unreal.
所有这些蜘蛛拥有不同的能力
Arachnids from all three groups possess...
帮助它们觅食
...varying strengths to help them search for food.
例如这一种澳洲产的蜘蛛
For example,the Delena spider,family Sparassidae...
它有跳跃的能力去捕食猎物
...has the ability to jump to catch its prey.
我能帮校刊拍一张吗
For the school paper?
只是古库基亚属的
Next,we have the net web spider,family Filistatidae...
非里特帝科的结网蜘蛛
...genus Kukulcania.
它能织出几乎跟
Spins a funnel - shaped web whose strands have a tensile strength...
建筑用钢索一样强韧的漏斗状蜘蛛网
...proportionately equal to the high - tension wires used in bridges.
-离我远一点  -不然会怎样
- Leave him alone. - Or what?
不然的话他老爸就会开除你老爸
Or his father will fire your father.
你老爸能怎样对付我  控告我吗
What's Daddy gonna do?Sue me?
怎么回事
What is going on?
谁再多说话我就给他不合格
The next person who talks will fail this course.
-这种蜘蛛利用  -我们走吧
- This spider... - Let's go.
反射动作猎食  它的反射神经反应非常快
...hunts using reflexes with nerve - conduction velocity so fast...
很多研究员认为它们有预知能力
...that some researchers believe it borders on precognition.
-能提早知道危险  -怪人
- An early awareness of danger. - Jerks.
蜘蛛第六感
A spider - sense.
你看那只蜘蛛
Hey,look at that spider.
有些蜘蛛会随着环境变色
Some spiders change colors to blend into their environment.
这是一种防御机制
It's a defense mechanism.
拜托  谁想知道这些
Peter,what makes you think I'd want to know that?
谁不想呢
Who wouldn't?
这五年来哥大基因研究中
Over five painstaking years,Columbia's research facility....
-你要去找她聊天  -不要啦  你去吧
- You gonna talk to her now? - Oh,no.Come on.You talk to her.
有了这些DNA的基因蓝图  将以往不可能的都变成真
With these DNA blueprints,we have begun what was once thought impossible.
-好恶心  -是啊  真恶心
- Disgusting. - Yeah,hateful little things.
我喜欢
I love them!
对啊  我也是
Yeah,me too.
你知道  蜘蛛能改变颜色
You know,spiders can change their color...
-以融入自然环境  -真的吗
- ...to blend into their environment. - Really?
-那是一种防御机制  -真酷
- Yeah,it's a defense mechanism. - Cool.
利用合成的核糖核酸去制造全新基因组
- transfer RNA to encode an entirely new genome...
再跟三种蜘蛛的基因结合在一起
...combining the genetic information from all three...
做出这15只超级蜘蛛
...into these 15 genetically designed super - spiders.
只有14只
There's 14.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
-有一只不见了  -对
- One's missing. - Yeah.
我猜有研究人员拿走了它做实验
I guess the researchers are working on that one.
你知道这是西岸最大的电子显微镜吗
Do you know that this is the largest electron microscope on the East Coast?
她在介绍时  你一直唠叨个不停
You were talking throughout that woman's entire presentation.
让我们谈谈该如何留心倾听
Let's talk about listening.
我不知道在私立学校是怎么样的
I don't know what it's like at those fancy private schools...
但在市公立高中
...but at Midtown High....
能拍张照片吗  我要拍一张有学生的
Could I take your picture?I need one with a student in it.
-当然可以  -太好了
- Sure. - Great.
你要我站哪儿  这儿吗
Where do you want me?Over here?
好啊
Yeah,that's great.
别把我拍得太难看
Don't make me look ugly.
怎么可能
That's impossible.
太完美了
Perfect.
-很好吗  -太棒了
- Is that good? - Great.
太棒了
That's great.
玛莉  我们走吧
M.J.,let's go!
等一下  谢谢
Wait.Thanks!
派克  走吧
Parker,let's do it.
新品种
[奥氏企业]
我们解决了平行滑翔和重力平衡的问题
We've solved the horizon glide and the balance issues.
我看过滑翔翼了
I've already seen the glider.
我不是为了这件事而来
That's not what I'm here for.
索将军  很高兴再见到你
General Slocum,good to see you again.
巴先生  费先生
Mr.Balkan,Mr.Fargas.
-诺曼  -奥斯本先生
- Norman. - Mr.Osborn.
很高兴董事会能大驾光临
Always a pleasure to have our board of directors visit.
我想看看体能增强计划的报告
I want the report on human performance enhancers.
我们让白老鼠接受汽化吸入测试  它们的体能增强了八倍
We tried vapor inhalation with rats.Their strength increased by 800%.
-太棒了  -有副作用吗
- Excellent. - Any side effects?
只有一次
Once.
其它的测试都很成功
All the tests since have been successful.
在那个出错的试验中  有什么副作用
In the trial that went wrong,what were the side effects?
暴力倾向  具有侵略性
Violence,aggression...
还有疯狂状态
...and insanity.
-你有什么建议  -那只是一次测试
- What do you recommend? - That was only one test.
除了史博士以外  大家都担保
Except for Dr.Stromm,our staff certifies the product...
-可以进行人体实验  -史博士
- ...ready for human testing. - Dr.Stromm?
我们必须把整个研究退回到方程式阶段
We need to take the whole line back to formula.
-退回到方程式阶段重新开始  -奥斯本博士
- Back to formula? - Dr.Osborn.
我老实跟你说
I'll be frank with you.
我从未支持过你的计划  那是前任负责人批准的
I never supported your program.We have my predecessor to thank for that.
索将军将支持探索航太公司
The general has approved Quest Aerospace...
制造人型盔甲的原型
...to build a prototype of their exoskeleton.
-两星期后进行测试  -如果你所谓的体能增强计划
- They test in two weeks. - And if your performance enhancers...
到那时候人体实验还不成功
...have not had a successful human trial by that date...
我就撤销你的研究经费  转给别人做
...I'm gonna pull your funding.I'm going to give it to them.
各位再见
Gentlemen.Ladies.
上帝说  来点光吧  马上就有光亮
And the Lord said,"Let there be light."And voila!There is light.
40瓦特柔和的灯光
Forty soft,glowing watts of it.
好孩子  上帝是会很高兴  不过小心别摔倒了
Good boy.God will be thrilled.Just don't fall on your ass.
我已经倒下了  梅
I'm already on my ass,May.
我这个当了35年的资深技师都被裁员了
When the plant's senior electrician is laid off after 35 years...
这还能算什么  我可是摔到谷底了
...what would you call it?I am on my ass.
把绿色的盘子递给我
Hand me that dish.The green one.
企业目前都在裁员
The corporation is downsizing the people...
以求增加盈利
...and upsizing their profits.
班  你会找到工作的
Oh,Ben,you'll get another job somewhere.
恩  看看报纸上有什么
Well,let's look in the paper and see.
有征人广告  看看有什么工作
There are the want ads.What do we got here?
电脑
Computer....
电脑销售员  电脑工程师  电脑分析师
Computer salesman,computer engineer,computer analyst.
天啊  现在连分析师都要懂电脑
My Lord,even the computers need analysts these days.
我都68岁  老了才学电脑太难  而且还要维持家计
I'm 68.I'm too old for computers,and besides,I have a family to provide for.
我爱你  彼得也爱你
I love you.And Peter loves you.
你是我见过最尽责的男人
You're the most responsible man I've ever known.
我们也苦过呀  还不是撑过来
We've been down - and - out before.But somehow,we survive.
孩子  你正好赶上  赶上晚餐
Hi,sweetie.You're just - Just in time for dinner.
你还好吧  课外活动如何
How you doing?How was the field trip?
我不舒服  我先去睡了
I don't feel well.I'm gonna go to sleep.
-你不吃一点吗  -我吃过了
- You won't have a bite? - Had a bite.
彼得  你有拍照吗
Did you get some pictures,Peter?
我要睡了  我很好
I gotta crash.Everything's fine.
他到底是怎么了
What's that all about?
我们在实验室
In this recombination lab...
利用合成的核糖核酸去制造全新基因组
...we use synthesized transfer RNA to encode an entirely new genome...
再跟三种蜘蛛的基因结合在一起
...combining the genetic information from all three...
做出这15只超级蜘蛛
...into these 15 genetically designed super - spiders.
奥博士  求求你  体能增强计划还没完成
Dr.Osborn,please.The performance enhancers aren't ready.
这次实验结果并不成功
The data just doesn't justify this test.
我最后一次请求你  我们不能这么做
Now,I'm asking you for the last time.We can't do this.
别这么胆小
Don't be a coward.
实验本来就有风险
Risks are part of laboratory science.
让我再另外安排一个医疗人员和自愿者
Let me reschedule,with a medical staff and a volunteer.
-只要给我两星期  -两星期
- Just give me two weeks. - Two weeks?
两星期内  我们拿不到合约  奥氏企业就完了
In two weeks?We'll have lost the contract to Quest and OSCORP will be dead.
有时候你只能靠自己
Sometimes you gotta do things yourself.
-给我催化剂  -做什么
- Get me the Promachloraperazine. - For what?
它能让增强剂更快进入血液
It begins catalyzation when the vapor hits the bloodstream.
人类演化了四万年
40,000 years of evolution...
无穷的潜力都还没完全发挥
...and we've barely tapped the vastness of human potential.
喔  真冷
Oh,that's cold.
诺曼
Norman?
Norman!
我的天
Oh,my God.
天啊
Oh,my God!
天啊  诺曼
Oh,my God!Norman!
回到方程式重新开始
Back to formula?
怪了
Weird.
-彼得  -嗯
- Peter? - Yeah?
你还好吧
Are you all right?
我很好
I'm fine.
-好一点吗  有改变吗  -改变
- Any better this morning?Any change? - Change?
有很大的改变
Yep.Big change.
-快一点  我们快迟到了  -对
- Well,hurry up.You'll be late. - Right.
好吧
Okay.
-真是的  -我以为你生病了
- Goodness me! - Jeez.I thought you were sick.
-我好多了  -看到了吗
- I got better. - See?
-再见了  -你有带你的午餐钱吗
- Bye,guys. - Have you got your lunch money?
别忘了下课后要回来粉刷厨房
Don't forget,we're painting the kitchen after school.
好呀  班叔叔  我回来前别开始啊
Sure,Uncle Ben.Don't start without me.
别放我鸽子
And don't start up with me.
年青人的荷尔蒙作祟
Teenagers.Raging hormones.They never change.
你是废物  你永远都是废物  跟你妈一样
You're trash!You're always gonna be trash!
-我要去上学了  -谁不让你去上学
- I have to go to school. - Who's stopping you?
嗨  玛莉
Hi,M.J.
Hey,M.J.
也许你不知道  我从6岁起就是你的邻居
I don't know if you realize this,but we've been neighbors since I was 6.
我在想  我可以跟你约会吗
And I was wondering if we could get together sometime?
我有车  上来吧
I got the car.Hop in.
一起出去玩玩  我不确定
Do something fun?Or,I don't know.
我觉得是多彼此了解的时候了
I thought it'd be time to get to know each other.
不要也行
Or not.
对不起  巴士满了
Sorry,Parker,the bus is full!
-停车  -坐出租车吧
- Stop the bus! - Catch a cab!
叫他停车
Tell him to stop.
-看  -白痴
- Check him out! - Dork!
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  你没事吧
Dad,are you all right?
哈利
Harry.
你躺在地上干嘛
What are you doing on the floor?
我不知道
I don't know.
你整晚都躺在地上吗
Have you been there all night?
昨晚我
Last night I was -
怎么了
What?
-我忘了  -奥斯本先生
- I don't remember. - Mr.Osborn?
先生  我叫她等一下的
Sir,I asked her to wait.
-我父亲不舒服  -奥先生  史博士死了
- My father's not feeling well  - Mr.Osborn,Dr.Stromm is dead.
什么
What?
在实验室找到他的尸体  是谋杀
They found his body in the lab.He's been murdered,sir.
-什么  -还有飞行衣和滑翔翼
- What? - And the flight suit and the glider....
-怎么样  -被偷了
- What about it? - Stolen,sir.
哇  好快的反应
Wow!Great reflexes!
-谢啦  -没什么
- Thanks. - No problem.
嘿  你原来有蓝眼珠  戴了眼镜都没有注意到
Hey,you have blue eyes.I didn't notice without your glasses.
换了隐形眼镜吗
You just get contacts?
回头见
Well,see you.
-怎么了  -他真奇怪
- What happened? - He's freaking weird.
你们看到吗
Did you see that?
派克
Parker?
-打起来了  -你觉得很好玩
- It's a fight! - Think you're funny?
-只是个意外  -我打掉你牙齿也是
- It was an accident. - So is my breaking your teeth.
-费许  住手  -我不想跟你打架
- Flash,stop. - I don't want to fight you.
-我也不想和你打  -揍他
- I wouldn't want to fight me neither. - Kick his ass.
哈利  快帮他
Help him,Harry.
他是怎么做到的
How'd he do that?
该帮谁呀
Which one?
你自己来吧
He's all yours,man.
费许  起来
Flash,get up!
天啊  派克  你真是怪胎
Jesus,Parker,you are a freak.
真是惊人
That was amazing.
我要走了  走吧
I'm out of here.Come on.
去  网子
Go,web!
飞啊
Fly.
射网
Up,up and away,web.
变身
Shazam!
快呀  吐丝
Go!Go!
吐丝
Go,web,go!
冲啊
Tallyho.
天才  饭菜在烤箱里
-她啤酒买回来了吗  -什么
- Is she back with the beer yet? - What?
我要啤酒
Bring me some beer.
-你自己去买  -我可是付了钱
- Get up off your ass. - I paid for beer -
-不要叫  -停
- Stop yelling. - Stop it!
你跟你妈一样蠢
You're as stupid as your mother.
你要去哪儿
Where's she going?Where you going?
你没洗盘子  盘子总要有人洗
The dishes aren't done.Somebody's gotta do dishes.
-你为什么不自己洗  -给我过来洗盘子
- Why don't you do them? - Get in here and do the dishes.
-你自己吃的自己洗  -我要出去
- You do them.They're yours,anyway. - I'm going out!
-你都听到了吗  -没有
- Were you listening to that? - No.
恩  我听到了  但我只是在倒垃圾
Well,I heard,but I was just taking out the trash.
我猜你都听到了
I guess you can always hear us.
每家人都会有吵架时
Everybody shouts.
你叔叔婶婶就不会
Your aunt and uncle don't.
喔  他们有时也吵得蛮大声的
Oh,they can scream pretty good sometimes.
今天在学校跟费许的事
Listen,M.J.,about today at school with Flash -
你吓死我们了
You really freaked us out.
对不起  他没事吧
I'm sorry.Is he okay?
他很高兴你没有给他一个黑眼圈
He's just happy you didn't give him a black eye for graduation.
你毕业后要去哪儿
So where are you going after you graduate?
我要搬进城里
I wanna move into the city.
希望能当个摄影师
And hopefully,get a job as a photographer.
一边工作一边上大学
Work my way through college.
你呢
What about you?
我也要进城
Headed for the city too.
我等不及要离开这儿
Can't wait to get out of here.
我想要
I wanna....
什么
What?
说来听听嘛
No,come on.Try me.
我想要
I wanna...
在舞台上
...act...
演戏
...on - stage.
真的吗
Really?
太好了
Oh,that's perfect.
你在学校话剧演出中都很出色
You were awesome in all the school plays.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
你演灰姑娘时  我哭得一塌糊涂
I cried like a baby when you played Cinderella.
彼得  那已是一年级的事了
Peter,that was first grade.
恩
Well...
你还是很棒
...even so.
有时候
Sometimes...
可以看得出来
...you know people.
你知道他们以后会做什么
You can just see what's coming.
你会做什么
What do you see coming for you?
我不知道
I don't know.
不管是什么  是我从未感觉过的
Whatever it is,it's something I never felt before.
那我呢
And what for me?
你
For you?
你会成为大明星
You're gonna light up Broadway.
你知道吗
You know...
你比实际上看起来高
...you're taller than you look.
我驼背
I hunch.
不要再驼背了
Don't.
玛莉  来试坐我的生日礼物
Hey,M.J.!Come take a ride in my new birthday present.
来吧
Come on.
我得走了
I gotta go.
再见
Bye.
-天啊  好漂亮  -对啊
- Oh,my God,it's gorgeous! - Yeah,right.
-看看他  -上车吧
- Look at it! - Hop in.
天啊  好酷的车
Oh,my God.What a cool car!
不错吧
Pretty tight,huh?
等一下听听他的音响  嘿  别刮到皮垫
Wait till you hear the sound system.Hey,don't scratch the leather.
酷车
Cool car.
价格合理的中古车
宾士  凯迪拉克轿车
捷豹  保时捷跑车
汽车城二手车
你最佳的选择
胜利TR-3
爱快罗密欧跑车
敞篷跑车
征业余摔角选手  上场三分钟
三千元  个性必须乐观
装束之选择
工具皮带
标志
颜色要鲜艳一点
你在干什么
What's going on in there?
我在健身  我没穿衣服
I'm exercising.I'm not dressed,Aunt May.
你最近怪怪的
Well,you're acting so strangely,Peter.
好啦  谢谢了
Okay.Thanks.
奥氏企业面临危机
奥诺曼会一蹶不振吗
他一定有烦恼  他可能不好意思说
Something's wrong.Maybe he's too embarrassed to tell me.
我也不好意思问
Maybe I'm too embarrassed to ask him.
我该怎么办
I just don't know anymore.
我要去图书馆  再见
I'm going to the library.See you later.
-等等  我载你去  -不用了  我坐地铁
- Wait.I'll drive you there. - I'll take the train.
我得去透透气  走吧
No,I need the exercise.Go on.Go,go.
-多谢了  班叔叔  -等一下  我们得谈谈
- Thanks for the ride,Uncle Ben. - Wait.We need to talk.
-以后再谈吧  -如果你愿意  我们现在就谈谈
- We can talk later. - Well,we can talk now.lf you let me.
我们要谈什么  一定要现在吗
What do we have to talk about? Why now?
我们好久没谈心了  我们都搞不懂你
We haven't talked for so long.May and I don't know who you are.
你不肯做家务  在房间里做一些怪实验
You shirk your chores.You have all those weird experiments in your room.
-你在学校里打架  -我说过不是我挑起的
- You start fights at school. - I told you I didn't start that fight.
-你不是打赢了吗  -我应该逃跑吗
- You sure finished it. - Was I supposed to run away?
你不应该逃  只是
No,you're not supposed to run away,but....
你在改变  在你这个年纪  我也一样
You're changing.I went through exactly the same thing at your age.
不  太不一样
No.Not exactly.
你在这几年的转变
These are the years when a man changes...
将决定未来你是怎么样的一个人
...into the man he's gonna become the rest of his life.
小心别误入歧途
Just be careful who you change into.
那个和你打架的人  也许是他错他活该
This guy,Flash Thompson,he probably deserved what happened.
但你打了他
But just because you can beat him up...
不代表你就是对  有权去打他
...doesn't give you the right to.
记住  能力愈大  责任愈重
Remember,with great power comes great responsibility.
你怕我变成流泯吗  别瞎担心了
Are you afraid I'll become a criminal?Quit worrying about me,okay?
事情不一样  我自己会解决的  别跟我说教
Something's different.I'll figure it out.Stop lecturing.
我不想跟你说教  我也不是你父亲
I don't mean to lecture or preach.And I know I'm not your father.
那你就别充父亲样子来说教
Then stop pretending to be!
对
Right.
我十点来接你
I'll pick you up here at 10.
巨无霸
Bone Saw!
巨无霸  灾难之王
-1  2  3  结束  -谁是第一名
- One,two,three.That's it! - Who's the man?
各位
Ladies and gentlemen...
巨无霸麦奎格
...give it up for Bone Saw McGraw.
奖金是三千元
For $3000...
谁有种上场跟巨无霸
...is there no one here man enough to stay in the ring...
大战三分钟
...for three minutes with this titan of testosterone?
谁
Who?
我知道是谁
I know who.
飞天人
The Flying Dutchman!
下一个
Next.
这不是轻量级比赛  下一个
There's no featherweight division here.Next.
不  我要参加
No,no.Sign me up.
好吧  你要明白如在这场比赛中受伤
Okay.You understand the NYWL is not responsible...
纽约摔角联盟绝不负责的吧
...for any injury you may and probably will sustain in said event?
你是自愿参加
And you're participating under your own free will?
过去吧  愿主保佑你  下一个
Down the hall to the ramp.May God be with you.Next.
告诉过你了
Told you!Told you!
胜利者
Winner!
下一个受害者
Next victim!
大家还想看吗
Are you ready for more?
巨无霸准备好了
Bone Saw is ready!
下一个受害者请上场  好吗
Will the next victim please enter the arena at this time?
如果他在笼子里撑得了三分钟
If he can withstand just three minutes in the cage with Bone Saw McGraw...
三千元奖金就会付给
...the sum of $3000 will be paid to -
-你叫什么名字  -人型蜘蛛
- What's your name,kid? - The Human Spider.
什么  那是你能想到最好的名字吗
That's it?That's the best you got?
-对  -差劲的名字
- Yeah. - Oh,that sucks.
三千元奖金
The sum of $3000 will be paid to...
就会付给恐怖的  致命的
...the terrifying,the deadly...
惊人的  蜘蛛侠
...the amazing Spider - Man!
-是“人型蜘蛛”  -上场吧
- It's "The Human Spider." - Get out there.
-不  他叫错名字了  -上场吧  笨蛋
- No,he got my name wrong. - Get out there,moron.
巨无霸会要你好看
Bone Saw will eat you up and spit you out.
你最好不要求饶
I hope you brought your mommy.
-我们拆烂你  -你要找别人去哭诉的
- We'll break you! - You'll need someone to cry to.
我要把你八只脚都扯下来
I'm gonna rip all eight of your feeble legs off one by one.
天啊
Oh,my God!
我的腿
Oh,my legs!
我的腿没感觉
Oh,God.I can't feel my legs.
杀杀杀杀
Kill!Kill!Kill!
杀死他
笼子  笼子  笼子
Cage!Cage!Cage!
笼子
Cage!
嘿
Hello?Guys?
可以麻烦警卫把铁笼锁起来吗
Will the guards please lock the cage doors at this time?
嘿  搞错了  我不是登记来做笼子打斗的
This is some kind of mistake.I didn't sign up for a cage match!
快把门打开  把铁链拿走
Unlock the thing!Take the chain off!
小怪胎
Hey,freak show!
你别想跑
You're going nowhere.
我要跟你好好玩三分钟
I got you for three minutes.
跟你好好玩三分钟
Three minutes of playtime.
-你跑到上面干嘛  -离你远远的
- What are you doing up there? - Staying away from you.
你的衣服真可爱  你丈夫给你的吗
That's a cute outfit.Did your husband give it to you?
把他解决掉
Finish him off!
踩扁这只蜘蛛
Smash him!
-打他  -用力
- Hit him! - Harder!
用力揍他
Kick his spider ass!
打他
Hit him!
1  2  3
One,two,three!
结束了  胜利者
That's it!That's it!Winner!
先生们女士们  新的胜利者  蜘蛛侠
Ladies and gentlemen,give it up for the new champion,Spider - Man!
快滚吧
Now get out of here.
一百元  广告说有三千的
A hundred bucks?The ad said 3000.
再看清楚一遍  猪头
Well,check it again,webhead.
是打三分钟三千元  而你只打了两分钟
It said three grand for three minutes.You pinned him in two.
有一百块就算你走运了
For that,I give you 100.You're lucky to get that.
我需要这笔钱
I need that money.
这可不关我的事
I missed the part where that's my problem.
-嘿  干嘛  -把钱放到袋子里
- Hey,what the hell - ? - Put the money in the bag.
快一点
Hurry up!
有人抢钱
Hey!He stole the gate!
拦住他
Stop that guy!
他抢了钱  拦住他
Stop him!He's got my money!
谢了
Thanks.
你干嘛把他放走
What's wrong with you?You let him go!
拦住他  快报警
Cut him off and call the cops!
你可以阻止他的  你却放他走
You could've taken that guy apart.Now he'll get away.
这可不关我的事
I missed the part where that's my problem.
-你们后退一点  -我看不到  发生了什么事
- You gotta get back. - I can't see.What happened?
一个老家伙
Old dude,man.
拜托  让我过
Come on,folks.Keep moving,please.Keep moving.Let's go!
-怎么了  -有人受伤了
- What happened? - Someone got hurt.
-请让开  让开  -退后
- Excuse me.Excuse me.Excuse me. - Stay back.
-退后  -那是我叔叔
- Stay back! - That's my uncle!
-怎么回事  -劫车  他被打了一枪
- What happened? - Carjacker.He's been shot.
我们叫了救护车  正在赶来
We just called the paramedics.They're on their way.
班叔叔
Uncle Ben?
Uncle Ben.
班叔叔
Uncle Ben?
彼得
Peter.
我在这儿  班叔叔
I'm here,Uncle Ben.
彼得
Peter.
有人目击凶手往南跑向第五大道
They got the shooter.He's headed south on Fifth.
三辆警车在追捕  各位  帮帮忙  退后
We got three cars in pursuit.All right,folks.Come on,move back.
派一辆警车到后面
Get a unit to the rear!
我守住后面了
I got the back!
什么人
Who's there?
别伤害我  给我一次机会
Don't hurt me.Give me a chance.Give me a chance!
你有给我叔叔机会吗  你有吗
What about my uncle?Did you give him a chance?Did you?
回答我
Answer me!
拦住他
Stop that guy!
谢了
Thanks.
再见了
See you.
站住  你被团团包围了
Freeze!We've got the place completely surrounded.
天啊
Oh,no.My God.
喔  不  天啊
Oh,no.Oh,my God.No!
[探索航太第六测试场]
-晚安  -将军  很高兴看到你
- Good evening. - General.Good to see you.
飞行衣的火力强大
Our exoskeleton's got real firepower,general.
如果真像你说的那么好  我马上签合约
Well,if it does what you say it can,I'll sign that contract tomorrow.
-准备起飞  -你对这测试很有信心
- He's clear!Go! - You're confident about this test?
当然  寇上尉是顶尖飞行员
Absolutely.Curtis is our top pilot.
奥氏企业怎么办
Now,what about your commitment to OSCORP?
我非常乐意让奥氏关门大吉
Nothing would please me more than to put Osborn out of business.
飞行前检查完毕  起飞
Preflight complete.Mark.
不明物体快速接近
An unidentified object is closing fast.
那是什么
What's that?
你看到吗
Can you see anything?
天啊
Oh,my God!
笑一个
- Say "chess." - Chess!
彼得
Peter!
亲爱的  我真为你骄傲  你今天看起来好帅
Darling,I'm so proud of you.You looked so handsome up there.
爸在纽约找到地方  到秋天时就可搬过去
Dad got the place in New York,so we're all set for fall.
-太好了  -你毕业了
- Great! - You made it.
这不是我第一次走眼了
It's not the first time I've been proven wrong.
-恭喜  -谢了  爸爸
- Congratulations. - Thanks,Dad.
彼得  你得到科学奖  太棒了
Peter,the science award.That's terrific.
是啊
Yeah.
我知道最近对你来说很难受
I know this has been a difficult time for you...
不过我要你好好享受今天
...but I want you to try to enjoy this day.
毕业典礼
Commencement:
这代表一个新的开始
The end of one thing,the start of something new.
我要跟你分手  这是你的戒指
I don't want to be with you anymore.Here's your ring.
知道吗  随便你
You know what?Whatever.
这是你的损失
Your loss.
你跟哈利情同手足  所以我们是一家人
You're like a brother to Harry.That makes you family.
你有需要就找我
And if you ever need anything,give me a call.
你要吃什么吗
Can I fix you something?
不  谢了
No,thanks.
我今天很想念他
I missed him a lot today.
我知道
I know.
我也很想他
I miss him too.
不过他今天也在那儿
But he was there.
我不由自主地想到我对他说的最后一句话
I can't help thinking about the last thing I said to him.
他想教我善恶之分  可我却不理他
He tried to tell me something important,and I threw it in his face.
你很爱他
You loved him...
他也很爱你
...and he loved you.
他一直都相信你会成材
He never doubted the man you'd grow into.
你也会做出一番大事
How you were meant for great things.
你不会让他失望
You won't disappoint him.
能力愈大  责任愈重
With great power comes great responsibility.
你一定要牢牢记住
Remember that,Pete.Remember that.
快一点
Hurry up!
蒙面人阻止抢劫案
他不是人  我哥哥看到他在林肯中心吐蜘蛛网
He's not a man.My brother saw him build a nest in Lincoln Center.
我想他是人  是个男人  搞不好是女人
I think he's human,a man.Could be a woman.
我们收购钻石
巴比  你看
Bobby.Get a load of this!
他一扬手就吐出丝  然后他就在上面爬行
He throws up his hands,ropes come out,and he climbs up them.
我看到他的蜘蛛网  他的标志  我就知道蜘蛛侠出现了
I see the web,his signature,and I know Spider - Man was here.
他会保护我们  保护市民
The guy protects us,protects the people.
他不是疯子就是怪胎
Some kind of freakyloo or something.
他很臭而且我不喜欢他
He stinks and I don't like him.
别动  小姐
Don't move,lady!
你的好邻居  蜘蛛侠上
有八只手的男人  好性感
Guy with eight hands.Sounds hot.
他的紧身裤还有那小小的紧身
Those tights and that tight little -
他打扮成蜘蛛  他看起来像昆虫
Dresses like a spider He looks like a bug
我们都该为他加油打气
But we should all just give him One big hug
小心  蜘蛛侠来了
Look out Here comes the Spider - Man
“谁是蜘蛛侠”  只是个罪犯
"Who is Spider - Man?"He's a criminal,that's who he is.
他是个公害  怎么会上我的头版封面
A vigilante,a public menace.Why's he on my front page?
詹先生  你太太在一线  她想知道
Mr.Jameson,your wife needs - Mr.Jameson,your wife needs
-第六版有问题  -头版才有问题
- There's a page six problem. - We have a page one problem.
-那么  -他是热门新闻
- Well? - He's news.
-客户不能等  -让他们等
- The clients can't wait. - They're about to.
-他在地铁救了六个人  -也许是他造成的灾难
- He pulled six people off a subway. - From a wreck he probably caused.
哪儿出事他就会在那儿  看  他看来像在逃离现场
Something goes wrong and he's there.Look!He's fleeing the scene.
他救了其它人  是个英雄
He's probably going to save somebody else.He's a hero!
那干么他要带面具  为什么要藏头露尾
Then why the mask?What's he got to hide?
她想要知道要用绵布还是绒布
She needs to know if you want chintz or chenille.
-用便宜的那一个  -是这样的
- Whichever's cheaper. - It's like this:
第六版的版面被重复预定了  梅西百货和大卖场都要
We double - booked page six.Macy's and Conway's both have -
-我们卖光4版  -卖光
- We sold out four printings. - Sold out?
每一份
Every copy.
明天头版要登蜘蛛侠照片  大卖场广告放到第七版
Tomorrow,Spider - Man,page one.Move Conway to page seven.
-第七版放不下  -那放第八版吧
- That's a problem. - Then make it page eight.
-办不到  -给我滚出去
- That can't be done. - Get out!
没有蜘蛛侠的照片  艾迪跟了半天  什么也拍不到
We can't get a decent picture.Eddie's on it,but we can barely see him.
怎么  他害羞吗
Aw,what is he,shy?
如果我们可以拍到茱莉亚罗勃兹的裸照  我们也可以拍到这个怪胎
If we can get Julia Roberts in a thong,we can get this weirdo.
登广告说  拍到蜘蛛侠就有奖金
On the front page: "Cash for a Spider - Man picture."
他不想成名  我就让他声名狼籍
He doesn't want to be famous?I'll make him infamous!
[月舞快餐]
滚开
Buzz off.
-玛莉  是我  彼得  -嗨
- M.J.,it's me,Peter. - Hi!
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing around here?
我在找工作  你呢
Begging for a job.How about you?
-我正要去试镜  -试镜  你在演戏了
- I'm headed to an audition. - An audition?So you're acting?
对
Yeah.
我找到一份工作  刚下班
I work steady.In fact,I just got off a job.
太好了
That's great.
-你的美梦成真  -大明星
- You're doing it.Living your dream. - Glamour girl!
你的收银机抽屉少了六块钱
Your drawer was short $6!
下次要扣薪水
Next time,I'll take it from your check.
对不起  华小姐  我在跟你讲话
Excuse me,Miss Watson?I'm talking to you!Hey!
是的  恩瑞  好啦  我听到了
Yes,Enrique!Okay?I get you.
下次小心点  最好不要再发生了
It better not happen no more.Don't roll your eyes at me.
梦想  嗯
Some dream,huh?
这没什么好丢脸的
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
-别告诉哈利  -别告诉哈利
- Don't tell Harry. - Don't tell Harry?
你们不是住在一起吗  我们正在约会  他没告诉你吗
Don't you guys live together?We're going out.Didn't he tell you?
喔  对
Oh,yeah.Right.
我想他讨厌我当服务生
I think he'd hate the idea of my waiting tables.
-他觉得那有点低贱  -那不是低贱  是份正当工作
- He'd think it was low or something. - It's not low.You have a job.
你知道  哈利并不是活在现实世界里
You know,Harry doesn't live on a little place I like to call Earth.
我想也是
No,I guess not.
谢谢  彼特
Thanks,Pete.
我们改天再聚聚
We should catch up sometime.
找晚上来吃午餐吧
Let's get some lunch some evening.
改天我会来找你
I'll come by and have some of your Moondance coffee some day.
-我不会告诉哈利  -别告诉他
- And I won't tell Harry. - Don't tell Harry.
我不会
I won't.
我不会告诉哈利
I won't tell Harry.
时间太完美了
Timing's perfect.Hey.
五份新合约  太棒了
Five new contracts.It'll be great.
我爸爸又来巡视了
Norman's making his weekly inspection.
不过大半的时间花在电话上
Spent half of it on the phone.
我很高兴你在这  我需要你的帮助
Look,man,I'm glad you're here.I need your help.I'm really lost here.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
你看起来像是在科学比赛惨败  屈居第二名的鬼样子
You look like you just got second place in the science fair.
我上班迟到  结果被康博士开除
I was late for work and Dr.Connors fired me.
你又迟到了
You were late again?
我不明白  你倒底跑哪去了
I don't get it.Where do you go all the time?
到处走走
Around.
彼得派克
Peter Parker.
-也许你该告诉我她是谁  -谁
- Maybe you'll tell me who she is. - Who?
-哈利正在约会的神秘女郎  -爸爸
- This mystery girl Harry's been dating. - Dad.
什么时候我可以见他
When do I get to meet her?
对不起  哈利没提过她
Well,sorry.Harry hasn't mentioned her.
彼得  你正在找新工作吧
Pete,you're probably looking for a job now,right?
爸爸  也许你能帮忙
Dad,maybe you can help him out.
-不用了  我自己找  -我可以打几个电话搞定
- I appreciate it,but I'll be fine. - I'll make a few calls.
我不能接受  我想自食其力  自己找工作
I couldn't accept it.I like to earn what I get.I'll find work.
我很佩服你
I respect that.
你想靠自己打天下
You want to make it on your own.
非常好
That's great.
你还有什么才能
What other skills do you have?
我想当摄影师
I was thinking about photography.
悬赏  蜘蛛侠照片
你好
Hello.
上吧  快
Let's go!Move it!
看着街上
Watch the street!
笑一个
Cheese!
垃圾
They're crap.
垃圾  全是垃圾
Crap,crap.Megacrap.
-我给你两百元  -价钱有点低啊
- I'll give you $200. - That seems a little low.
那就去找别人
Take them somewhere else.
-你太太说你订的磁砖缺货  -那就铺地毯吧
- Your wife says the tile's out of stock. - We'll put a rug there.
坐下  给我看
Sit down.Give me that.
给你三百元  这是标准价格
Give you 300.That's the standard fee.
-把照片刊在头版  -标题呢
- Scrap page one.Run that. - Headline?
蜘蛛侠  英雄还是公害  号角日报独家照片
"Spider - Man,Hero or Menace?Exclusive Photos."
-公害  他在保护  -你拍照就好
- Menace?He was protecting  - You take the photos...
我负责想标题
...I'll make up the headlines.Okay?
-是的  先生  -很好
- Yes,sir. - Goody.
拿到柜台  她会付你钱
Give this to the girl up front.She'll see you get paid.
-我想要一份正职工作  -你只能当特聘兼职摄影师
- I'd like a job,sir. - No jobs.Freelance.
对你最好
Best thing for you.
你只要拍到那个跳梁小丑  我就付你钱
You bring me more shots of that clown,maybe I'll buy them.
但我没说要给你工作
But I never said you have a job.Meat.
我最多在新年送你一串腊肠  快给我更多的照片
I'll send you a box of Christmas meat.Bring me more photos.
-你好  -你好
- Hi. - Hi.
詹先生要我给你这个
Mr.Jameson told me to give that to you.
-欢迎来到号角日报  -谢谢你
- Welcome to the Daily Bugle. - Thank you.
我是彼得派克
I'm Peter Parker.
是个摄影师
I'm a photographer.
我看得出来
Yes.I can see that.
从今天起
As of today...
奥氏企业超越探索航太
...OSCORP Industries has surpassed Quest Aerospace...
成为美国军方的最大供应商
...as the principal supplier to the United States military.
也就是说  各位董事
In short,ladies and gentlemen of the board...
成本降低  利润增加
...costs are down,revenues are up...
而我们公司的股价  则前所未见的涨高
...and our stock has never been higher.
实在太好  所以我们决定要把公司卖掉
Wonderful news,Norman.That's why we're selling the company.
说什么
What?
探索航太目前正在集资扩大规模
Quest is recapitalizing in the wake of the bombing.Expanding.
他们开出来的收购条件很好
They made a tender offer we can't ignore.
怎么不知会我
Why wasn't I told?
他们不希望引起资深管理阶层斗争
They don't want a power struggle with entrenched management.
如果你在的话  收购交易就拉倒
The deal is off if you come with it.
董事会将在30天内宣布联署罢免你
The board expects your resignation in 30 days.
你们不能这么做
You can't do this to me.
这公司是我一手创立的
I started this company.
你们知道我为此牺牲了多少吗
You know how much I sacrificed?!
-拜托  麦克斯  -诺曼  董事会已一致通过罢免你
- Oh,Max.Please. - Norman,the board is unanimous.
我们将选在世界嘉年华会之后宣布
We're announcing the sale after the World Unity Festival.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你出局了  诺曼
You're out,Norman.
是吗
Am I?
欢迎来到探索航太的世界嘉年华会
Welcome to OSCORP Industries Unity Day Festival.
请鼓掌欢迎梅西格蕾
Let's hear it for Macy Gray.
纽约市民惊恐蜘蛛之吻
玛莉  你怎么不穿黑色礼服
M.J.,why didn't you wear the black dress?
你要让我爸爸有好印像  他喜欢黑色
Just,I wanted to impress my father.He loves black.
也许我穿什么他也喜欢  至少你觉得我很美
Well,maybe he'll be impressed no matter what.You think I'm pretty.
我觉得你很漂亮
I think you're beautiful.
我的酒忘了放在里面
I forgot my drink inside.
-嗨  费先生  -嗨  哈利
- Oh,hi,Mr.Fargas. - Oh,Harry.
-你看到我爸爸吗  -他今天不一定会来
- Have you seen my father? - Well,I'm not sure if he's coming.
-那是什么  -一定是今年的新玩意
- What is that? - Must be new this year.
那是什么
What is that?
那是我们的滑降翼
That's our glider!
那是什么玩意
What the hell was that?
紧急状况
Code three!
-喔  天啊  哈利  -玛莉
- Oh,my God!Harry! - M.J.!
哈利  救救我
Harry!Help me!Harry!
我出局了  是吗
Out,am I?
-玛莉  -哈利
- Mary Jane! - Harry!
你好  亲爱的
Hello,my dear.
是蜘蛛侠
It's Spider - Man!
-快走啊  -比利
- Come on.Move,kid. - Billy!
快去救他
Somebody help him!
不
No!
妈妈
Mommy!
-站住  -我投降
- Hold it! - I surrender.
-喔  糟了  -不要动
- Oh,boy. - Hold it right there!
好厉害
Impressive.
-玛莉  -救命啊  快来救我
- Mary Jane! - Help!Someone please help me!
抓稳了
Hold on!
小心
Watch out!
后会有期  蜘蛛侠
We'll meet again,Spider - Man!
这比坐地铁快吧
Well,beats taking the subway.
别理我们  她只是要用一下电梯
Don't mind us.She just needs to use the elevator.
等一下
Wait.
你是谁
Who are you?
-你知道我是谁  -我知道吗
- You know who I am. - I do?
你的好邻居蜘蛛侠
Your friendly neighborhood Spider - Man.
不可思议  你说不可思议是什么意思
Incredible?What do you mean he's incredible?
不  好吧  等一下  待在那里  我等一下就过去
No.All right,wait.Stay there.I'll come over.
我就过去
No,I'm gonna come -
好吧  明天一早能打给我吗
All right.Fine.Will you call me in the morning?
我们一起吃早饭
And we'll go and have breakfast and...
我想送你一些东西
...I want to buy you something.
因为我想要  可以让你感觉好一点
Because I want to.It'll make you feel better.
你说不可思议是什么意思
Okay.And what do you mean,incredible?
好啦  对不起  晚安
All right.I'm sorry.Sleep tight.
别做恶梦
Don't let the bedbugs -
她没事  只是受到惊吓
She's all right.She's just a little rattled.
我知道早该跟你说的
Look,Pete,I should have told you about us.
你也知道我喜欢她
But you should know I'm crazy about her.
谁叫你一直没有行动
It's just,you know,you never made a move.
你说的对
You're right.
是我没有行动
I didn't.
我要去睡了
I'm gonna get some rest.
我待会再睡
I'm gonna stay up for a while.
那是什么
What was that thing?
我不知道
I don't know.
不管是什么  一定要阻止他
Whatever it is,somebody has to stop it.
有人在吗
Somebody there?Somebody.
当然有人
Somebody.
是谁说的
Who said that?
别装一副无辜样
Don't play the innocent with me.
你一直都知道
You've known all along.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
跟着那股直冲你脑门的寒意
Follow the cold shiver running down your spine.
我就在那儿
I'm right here.
我不明白
I don't understand.
以为这全是巧合吗
Did you think it was coincidence?
你身上发生这么多好事
So many good things,all happening for you.
这全是为了你  诺曼
All for you.Norman.
你想要什么
What do you want?
说你不敢说的
To say what you won't.
做你不敢做的
To do what you can't.
除掉挡住你的每一个障碍
To remove those in your way.
董事会委员们
The board members.
你杀了他们
You killed them.
是我们杀了他们
We killed them.
我们
We?
记得吗
Remember?
你在实验室的小意外
Your little accident in the laboratory.
体能增强剂
The performance enhancers.
答对了  就是我-你最伟大的发明
Bingo.Me!Your greatest creation.
这是你这辈子最想要的
Bringing you what you've always wanted:
超乎想像的超能力
Power beyond your wildest dreams.
这只是刚开始
And it's only the beginning.
只有一个人能阻止我们
There's only one who can stop us.
也许他能加入我们
Or imagine if he joined us.
蜘蛛侠和绿恶魔
Spider - Man.And the Green Goblin.
绿恶魔  喜欢吗  是我想出来的
The Green Goblin.You like that?Made it up myself.
-这些怪胎需要有个名字  -詹先生
- These weirdos all got to have a name. - Mr.Jameson -
-霍夫曼  -什么事
- Hoffman! - Yeah?
替“绿恶魔”申请版权  有人用这个名字就要付我钱
Copyright "Green Goblin."I want a quarter every time it's said.
绿坏蛋如何
How about "Green Meanie"?
蜘蛛侠没有攻击别人  这是恶意中伤
Spider - Man wasn't attacking.That's slander.
才不是  我不同意
It is not.I resent that.
中伤是说话  印出来就是毁谤了
Slander is spoken.In print,it's libel.
你不相信任何人
You don't trust anybody.
我信任我的理发师
I trust my barber.
蜘蛛侠的律师吗
Are you his lawyer?
让他告吧  大家都想发财  这让这个国家
Let him sue.Get rich like a normal person.That's what made this country -
姓詹的  你这混蛋
Jameson,you slime.
是谁拍到蜘蛛侠的照片
Who takes the pictures of Spider - Man?
-不知道  他都用寄的  -你骗人
- I don't know.His stuff comes by mail. - Liar!
-我发誓  -他能带我找到蜘蛛侠
- I swear. - He's the one who can bring me to him.
-我不知道他是谁  -你真没用
- I don't know who he is. - You are useless.
把他放下来
Set him down,tough guy.
-说来就来  -我就知道你们是同党
- Speak of the devil. - I knew you two were in this together!
大人说话  小孩不可插嘴
Kiddo,let Mom and Dad talk for a minute.
安睡吧
Sleep....
醒来吧  小蜘蛛  醒来
Wake up,little spider.Wake up.
放心  你没死  还没有
No,you're not dead yet.
你只是暂时
Just paralyzed...
被麻痹了
...temporarily.
你真的很不可思议  蜘蛛侠
You're an amazing creature,Spider - Man.
你和我是那么的相像
You and I are not so different.
我跟你不同  你是个杀人凶手
I'm not like you.You're a murderer.
只是人各有志
Well,to each his own.
这是我的选择  而你选择当超级英雄
I chose my path,you chose the way of the hero.
大众对你只有三分钟热度
And they found you amusing for a while,the people of this city.
他们最想看到的是
But the one thing they love more than a hero...
英雄的失败  殒落和死亡
...is to see a hero fail,fall,die trying.
不管你替他们做了多少好事  最后他们都只会憎恨你
In spite of everything you've done for them,eventually,they will hate you.
那又何必呢
Why bother?
-因为这是对的  -事实是这样子的
- Because it's right. - Here's the real truth.
纽约有八百万市民
There are eight million people in this city.
他们的存在只有一个作用
And those teeming masses exist for the sole purpose...
把少数杰出的天才举在他们肩上
...of lifting the few exceptional people onto their shoulders.
像是你  我
You,me...
这种天才
...we're exceptional.
我大可以一脚把你踩扁
I could squash you like a bug right now.
但我给你一个选择  加入我
But I'm offering you a choice.Join me.
想像一下我们可以共同完成的大事
Imagine what we could accomplish together.
可以开创未来
What we could create.
还是我们可以大肆破坏
Or we could destroy.
为了你所谓的理想  死伤无辜百姓
Cause the deaths of countless innocents in selfish battle...
直到我们双方倒下为止  这才是你想要的吗
...again and again and again until we're both dead.Is that what you want?
想想看吧  大英雄
Think about it,hero.
蜘蛛侠和绿恶魔狼狈为奸
全面通缉
不管你替他们做了多少好事  最后他们都只会憎恨你
In spite of everything you've done for them,eventually,they will hate you.
市民呼吁当局扑灭害虫
又是我
It's me again.
你的试镜如何
How was your audition?
-你怎么知道  -我的消息灵通  你妈妈
- How'd you know? - The hot line.Your mom...
跟我婶婶说的  婶婶跟我说的
...told my aunt,told me.
你是来看我吗
So you just came by?
我正好路过  想看一下可爱的面孔
I was in the neighborhood.Needed to see a friendly face.
我坐公车和计程车大老远跑来
I took two buses and a cab to get in the neighborhood,but....
试镜如何
So how'd it go?
他们叫我再回去上演技课
They said I needed acting lessons.
肥皂剧要我去上演技课
A soap opera told me I needed acting lessons.
我请你吃汉堡  价钱上限到7.84元
Let me buy you a cheeseburger.The sky's the limit,up to $7.84.
我很想吃
I'd like a cheeseburger.
不过我要跟哈利约了吃晚饭
Oh,but I'm going out to dinner with Harry.
一起来吧
Come with us.
不  谢了  你们之间如何
No,thanks.How's it going with...?
算了  不关我的事
Never mind.That's none of my business.
是吗
It's not?
那你干嘛这么关心
Why so interested?
我没有
I'm not.
你没有
You're not?
-我干嘛要关心  -我不知道
- Well,why would I be? - I don't know.
为什么
Why would you be?
我  我不知道
I,that's a -
我不知道
I don't know.
可惜你不跟我们一起来
Sorry you won't come with us.
我要走了
I'd better run,tiger.
嘿  看
Hey,check it out,man.
别走  美女
Come on,man.
你去哪儿  美女  来嘛
Hey,where you going,baby?Come on!
放开我
Get off me!
等等
Wait!
你好像有惹上麻烦的习惯
You have a knack for getting in trouble.
而你也好像有救我的习惯  超级英雄来当我的保镖
You have a knack for saving my life.I think I have a superhero stalker.
我刚巧在附近
I was in the neighborhood.
你真厉害
You are amazing.
有些人不这么想
Some people don't think so.
-你真的很棒  -有仰慕者真好
- But you are. - Nice to have a fan.
这次我能谢你吗
Do I get to say thank you this time?
等等
Wait.
我要进去救我的孩子
Let me in!My baby's in there!
-让我进去  -屋顶就快塌了
- Let me go! - The roof's collapsing!
-谁来救救我的孩子  -屋顶就快塌了
- Somebody save my baby! - The roof's about to collapse!
你们看上面
Look!Up there!
请救救我的孩子
Save my baby,please!
不
No!
-没事了  他很安全  -我的宝贝
- It's okay.Your baby's fine. - Oh,my baby!
上帝保佑你  蜘蛛侠
God bless you,Spider - Man.Bless you.
别让他跑掉
Don't let him get away!
等等  你被捕了  我要带你回警局
Hold it!You're under arrest.I'm taking you in.
天啊  还有人在上面
Oh,my God,there's somebody still up there!
我要去救人
I'm going.
-我会等你回来  -我不会再回来
- I'll be here when you get back. - Not coming back.
快去吧
Go!Go!
你在哪儿
Where are you?
我会把你救出去
I'm gonna get you out of here!
没事了
It's okay.
你一点新意也没有
You're pathetically predictable.
老是飞蛾扑火
Like a moth to the flame.
我的提议怎么样
What about my generous proposal?
你想不想加入我
Are you in or are you out?
-我看你是丧心病狂了  -答错了
- It's you who's out.Out of your mind. - Wrong answer.
喔  太棒了
Oh,great.
没有人能拒绝我
No one says no to me!
-拜托你别闹了  可以吗  -哈利  放轻松
- M.J.,will you stop goofing around? - Harry,relax.
他来了
He's here.
好了吗
Are you ready?
梅婶  抱歉迟到了
Aunt May.I'm sorry I'm late.
工作忙得要命  我带了水果蛋糕来
Work was murder.I picked up a fruitcake.
谢谢你  奥斯本先生  很高兴你抽空过来
Thank you,Mr.Osborn.We're so glad you could come.
这位可爱的小姐是
Who is this lovely young lady?
这是我父亲奥诺曼  爸爸  这是华玛莉
I'd like you to meet my father.Dad,this is Mary Jane Watson.
你好  我一直想见你
I've been looking forward to meeting you.
-感恩节快乐  -彼得呢
- Happy Thanksgiving,sir. - Now,where is Peter?
他最好记得买红莓酱
He'd better remember that cranberry sauce.
奇怪  我不知道他在家
Oh,that's weird.I didn't know he was here.
彼得
Peter?
是你吗
Is that you?
How strange.There's nobody here.
-他有点邋遢  不是吗  -天才都是这样
- Bit of a slob,isn't he? - All brilliant men are.
-大家好  -彼得
- Hey,everyone. - Oh,Peter!
外面真是混乱
It's a jungle out there.
我好不容易才买到酱
Had to beat an old lady with a stick to get these cranberries.
谢谢  现在  请大家坐下吧
Thank you.Now then,everybody sit down...
让我们祷告
...and we can say grace.
好了
Here we go.
-来了  -看起来很好吃
- There we are. - It looks delicious.
请你切火鸡
Will you do the honors?
怎么了  彼特  你在流血
Why,Peter,you're bleeding.
我走在街上  被个骑脚踏车的撞伤了
I stepped off a curb and got clipped by one of those bike messengers.
让我看看
Well,let me see.
喔  我的天啊
Oh,my goodness.
-看起来很严重  -没什么
- That looks awful. - No,it's nothing.
我去拿急救箱  接着再来祷告
I'll get the first - aid kit.Then we'll say grace.
你们第一次在这儿过感恩节  我们要照规矩来
This is the boys' first Thanksgiving here,and we'll do things properly.
你是怎么受伤的
How did you say that happened?
骑脚踏车的
Bike messenger.
把我撞伤了
Knocked me down.
-不好意思  我得走了  -为什么
- If you'll excuse me,I've got to go. - Why?
我突然想到一件事
Something has come to my attention.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我没事  谢谢你  大家慢用
I'm fine,just fine.Thank you,Mrs.Parker.Everyone.
-请享用水果蛋糕  -爸爸
- Enjoy the fruitcake. - Dad!
我想让你多认识玛莉  但你现在却要离开
I planned this so you'd meet M.J.,and now you have to leave?
我得走了
I've got to go.
-她对我很重要  -拜托你看清楚一点
- This girl is important to me. - Harry,please.Look at her.
你以为她是真的喜欢你吗
Think she's sniffing around because she likes your personality?
-你在说什么  -你妈妈也很漂亮
- What are you saying? - Your mother was beautiful.
她们都很漂亮  直到一闻到钱就变成豺狼
They're all beautiful until they're snarling after your money like wolves.
你错了  爸爸
You're wrong,Dad.
给你一个忠告怎对女友
A word to the not - so - wise about your girlfriend:
把她弄到手了就甩掉她
Do what you need to with her,then broom her fast.
谢谢你帮我辩解  哈利
Thanks for sticking up for me,Harry.
-你都听到了  -全部人都听到那混蛋说的话了
- You heard? - Everyone heard that creep.
他可是我老爸  我只恨我什么也比不上他
That creep is my father.With luck,I'll be half of what he is.
你不懂就别乱说
Shut up about stuff you don't understand!
奥哈利
Harry Osborn!
对不起
I'm sorry,Aunt May.
蜘蛛侠是战无不胜的
Spider - Man is all but invincible.
但是我们能毁了彼得
But Parker,we can destroy him.
我办不到
I can't.
我绝不容许背叛的行为
Betrayal must not be countenanced.
一定要给他一点教训
Parker must be educated.
我该怎么做
What do I do?
教教他什么是痛苦和失去
Instruct him in the matters of loss and pain.
让他受苦  让他生不如死
Make him suffer.Make him wish he were dead.
然后呢
Yes?
然后再杀了他
And then grant his wish.
怎么做
But how?
聪明人不会直接攻击敌人
The cunning warrior attacks neither body nor mind.
快教我
Tell me how!
你要攻心
The heart,Osborn.
先向他的亲人下手
First,we attack his heart.
赐给我们今天的食物  原谅我们的过错
Give us this day our daily bread,and forgive us our trespasses...
也让我们原谅别人的过错
...as we forgive those who trespass against us.
别让我们受到诱惑  拯救我们
Lead us not into temptation,but deliver us -
拯救我们
Deliver us!
快说完
Finish it!
-快说完  -不受恶魔侵犯
- Finish it! - From evil!
两毫克的静脉注射
Two milligrams IV.
去拿血压计来
Get the BP.
梅婶怎么了  她没事吧
Aunt May.Is she gonna be okay?What happened?
请你出去
You have to leave.
-怎么了  -好可怕的双眼
- What happened? - Those eyes!
可怕的黄色眼晴
Those horrible yellow eyes!
他知道我是谁
He knows who I am.
对不起
I'm sorry.
-她还好吧  -她会没事的
- Will she be okay? - She'll be fine.
她整天都在睡
She's been sleeping all day.
-谢谢你来探望她  -当然
- Thanks for coming. - Of course.
你还好吧  我是说那晚
How are you?You okay about the other night?
我很好  我不该丢下梅婶
Yeah,I'm fine.I just felt bad about leaving Aunt May.
-你跟哈利谈过吗  -他打过电话给我
- Have you talked to Harry? - He called me.
我还没打回去
I haven't called him back.
事实上
The fact is...
-我爱上另一个人了  -真的吗
- ...I'm in love with somebody else. - You are?
至少我认为是这样
At least I think I am.
-现在谈不太好  -不会的  说吧
- It's not the time to talk about it. - No.Go on.
他叫什么
Would I know his name,this guy?
你一定觉得我很傻
You'll think I'm a little girl with a crush.
尽管说吧
Trust me.
很好笑
It's funny.
他救了我两次  但我却没见过他的脸
He's saved my life twice,and I've never even seen his face.
-原来是他  -你在嘲笑我
- Oh.Him. - You're laughing at me.
没有  我知道  他真的很酷
No,I understand.He is extremely cool.
你觉得他们说的那些坏事是真的吗
But do you think it's true,all the terrible things they say?
不是  蜘蛛侠绝对不是坏人
Not Spider - Man,not a chance in the world.
我算是认识他
I know him a little bit.
我是他非正式的摄影师
I'm sort of his unofficial photographer.
-他有提到过我吗  -有啊
- Has he mentioned me? - Yeah.
他怎么说
What'd he say?
我说
I said....
他问我觉得你怎么样
He asked me what I thought about you.
你怎么说
And what did you say?
我说  蜘蛛侠
I said,"Spider - Man."
我说  玛莉最大的优点
I said,"The great thing about M.J...
是
...is...
当你看着她的双眼
...when you look in her eyes...
而她也注视着你时
...and she's looking back in yours...
一切好像都
...everything feels...
变得特别了
...not quite normal.
因为你会同时
Because you feel...
感到更坚强
...stronger...
而同时也更软弱
...and weaker at the same time.
你会感到兴奋
You feel excited...
同时也会感到
...and at the same time...
害怕
...terrified.
你也不大清楚那是什么感觉
The truth is,you don't know what you feel...
只知道你想成什么样的人
...except you know what kind of man you want to be.
就像是完成了
It's as if you've...
遥不可及的梦想
...reached the unreachable...
却一点也没有准备好
...and you weren't ready for it."
这是你说的
You said that?
差不多是这样
Well,something like that.
爸爸
Dad?
爸爸  是你吗
Dad,is that you?
怎么了
What is it?
你没看错玛莉  你都说对了
You were right about M.J.You're right about everything.
她爱上彼得了
She's in love with Peter.
-派克吗  -是
- Parker? - Yeah.
他爱不爱她
And how does he feel about her?
他从四年级就暗恋她了
He's loved her since the 4th grade.
他装作没有  不过彼特根本没有爱过其它人
He pretends like he doesn't,but there's no one Peter cares for more.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我都没有好好陪你
I haven't always been there for you,have I?
你很忙  你是重要人物  我了解
You're busy.You're an important man.I understand.
这不是借口
That's no excuse.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you.
我不该冷落你  我会补偿你的
I've lost sight of that somewhere.But I'll make it up to you.
我要替你讨回公道
I'm going to rectify certain inequities.
醒来  小蜘蛛
Wake up,little spider.
醒来
Wake up.
回家吧  亲爱的
Go home,dear.
你看来遭透了
You look awful.
-你看来美极了  -谢谢
- And you look beautiful. - Thank you.
-我不想丢下你  -我很安全
- I don't like to leave you here. - But I'm safe here.
-我能为你做什么  -你做的够多了
- Can I do anything for you? - You do too much.
半工半读还得陪我  你又不是超人
College,a job,all this time with me.You're not Superman,you know.
你终于笑了
A smile.Finally.
自从玛莉走了之后就没看你笑过了
Haven't seen one of those on your face since Mary Jane was here.
你应该是睡着的
You were supposed to be asleep.
玛莉搬到隔壁你才六岁
You know,you were about 6 years old when M.J.'s family moved in next door.
当她下车时  你一看到她
When she got out of the car,and you saw her for the first time...
你就抓着我说  梅婶  她是天使吗
...you grabbed me and said,"Aunt May,is that an angel?"
-我这么说吗  -当然了
- Gee,did I say that? - You sure did.
喔  可是哈利爱她
Well,Harry's in love with her.
-她仍然是他的女友  -那不是她的决定是吗
- She's still his girl. - Well,isn't that up to her?
-她并不了解我  -因为你不让她了解你
- She doesn't really know who I am. - Because you won't let her.
你总是这么内向
You're so mysterious all the time.
告诉我  让她知道你有多喜欢她
Tell me,would it be so dangerous...
有什么关系呢
...to let Mary Jane know how much you care?
大家都看得出来
Everybody else knows.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
但是
But....
快接呀
Come on,pick up.
-嗨  玛莉  -听到哔声请留言
- Hey M.J. - Hi.Sing your song at the beep.
玛莉  我是彼得  你在吗
M.J.,it's Peter.You there?
喂  你在吗
Hello?You there?
我想知道你可好  给我回电  好吗
I'm just calling to check up on you.Will you call me when you get in?
好吧
All right,well....
别走
Don't....
别走暗巷
Don't go up any dark alleys.
喂
Hello?
蜘蛛侠能出来玩吗
Can Spider - Man come out to play?
她在哪儿
Where is she?
-那是什么  -真酷
- What is that? - That's cool!
这只小蜘蛛跑到喷泉旁
The itsy - bitsy spider Went up the water spout
马上就被绿恶魔杀光光
Down came the goblin And took the spider out
绿恶魔  你干了什么
Goblin,what have you done?
蜘蛛侠  这就是为什么傻瓜才会去当英雄
Spider - Man!This is why only fools are heroes.
因为你永远不知道
Because you never know...
哪一天哪个疯子会出个残酷的难题
...when some lunatic will come along with a sadistic choice:
让你选心爱的女人死
Let die the woman you love...
还是让无辜的小孩死
...or suffer the little children.
-蜘蛛侠  -救我们
- Spider - Man! - Save us!
救我们
Save us!
快决定吧  蜘蛛侠
Make your choice,Spider - Man...
当一个英雄就是要付出代价
...and see how a hero is rewarded.
别这样做  绿恶魔
Don't do it,Goblin!
他们的命运掌握在你手上
We are who we choose to be.
-现在  选吧  -不
- Now,choose! - No!
大家抓稳了
Everybody stay still!
嘿  上面的
Ahoy up there!
我们要把船开到你的正下方
We're gonna bring the barge right under you.
-他又回来了  -听好  我要你爬下去
- He's coming back! - Listen.I need you to climb down.
-我做不到  -你可以的
- I can't. - Yes,you can!
玛莉  你可以做到  而你必须做
M.J.,you can do it.You have to.
相信我
Trust me.
抓紧  快下去
Hold on tight and go quickly.
-快  -我做不到
- Hurry! - I can't.I can't do it.
抓紧了  玛莉
Hang on,Mary Jane!
-他不行了  -他行的
- He's not gonna make it. - He's gonna make it!
死亡的时间到了
It's time to die.
-这个是给你的  -我们应该狠狠揍你
- I got something for you! - We ought to kick your ass!
别惹蜘蛛侠  你在对付救小孩的人
Leave Spider - Man alone!You'd pick on a guy saving kids?
你敢惹蜘蛛侠就是惹上全纽约的人
You mess with Spidey,you mess with New York!
你惹上他就得对付我们全部
You mess with one of us,you mess with all of us!
蜘蛛侠  小心
Spider - Man,watch out!
你选择了悲惨的命运
Misery,misery,misery.That's what you've chosen.
我把你当朋友
I offered you friendship...
你却不屑一顾
...and you spat in my face.
没戏唱了  蜘蛛侠
You've spun your last web,Spider - Man.
如果你没这么自私  我就让你的小女友
Had you not been so selfish,your girlfriend's death...
死得痛快
...would have been quick.
但是现在你把我惹火了
But now that you've really pissed me off...
我要慢慢地把她折磨到死
...I'm gonna finish her nice and slow.
我和玛莉
M.J.and I...
一定会玩得很开心
...we're gonna have a hell of a time.
彼得  住手
Peter,stop!
住手  是我
Stop!It's me.
奥先生
Mr.Osborn.
幸好是你
Thank God for you.
你杀死了在阳台上的那些人
You killed those people on that balcony.
是绿恶魔干的  与我无关
The Goblin killed!I had nothing to do with it!
别  别让心魔再控制我
Don't let him take me again.
求求你  保护我
I beg you.Protect me.
是你想杀死梅婶和玛莉
You tried to kill Aunt May.You tried to kill Mary Jane.
但我没想过要杀你
But not you.
我想阻止心魔  却阻止不了
I tried to stop it.But I couldn't stop it.
我绝不会伤害你
I would never hurt you.
我早就知道
I knew from the beginning...
要是我出事
...if anything ever happened to me...
你一定会帮助我
...it was you I could count on.
你  彼得派克  一定会救我  你果然做到了
You,Peter Parker,would save me,and so you have.
谢天谢地
Thank God for you.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
相信我  就像我相信你一样
Believe in me as I believed in you.
我就像是你的父亲
I've been like a father to you.
当我的儿子吧
Be a son to me now.
我只有一个父亲
I have a father.
他的名字是班派克
His name was Ben Parker.
永别了  蜘蛛侠
Godspeed,Spider - Man.
彼得
Peter.
别告诉哈利
Don't tell Harry.
你做了什么
What have you done?
What have you done?!
我很抱歉  哈利
I'm so sorry,Harry.
我知道失去父亲时的感受
I know what it's like to lose a father.
我没失去他  他是被夺走的
I didn't lose him.He was stolen from me.
总有一天  蜘蛛侠会付出代价
One day Spider - Man will pay.
我发誓要让蜘蛛侠付出代价
I swear on my father's grave,Spider - Man will pay.
幸好还有你  彼得
Thank God for you,Peter.
你是我唯一的亲人
You're the only family I have.
不管我怎么做
No matter what I do...
怎么努力
...no matter how hard I try...
我最爱的人都会付出代价
...the ones I love will always be the ones who pay.
班派克之墓  受人敬爱的丈夫和叔叔
你一定很想念他
You must miss him so much.
失去他很难过
It's been so hard without him.
我一直想跟你说一件事
There's something I've been wanting to tell you.
当我在桥上
When I was up there...
我以为自己快死了
...and I thought I was gonna die...
我心里只想念一个他
...there was only one person who I was thinking of.
但他不是我一直以为会想到的人
And it wasn't who I thought it'd be.
可他是你  彼得
It was you,Pete.
我一直在想
I kept thinking:
如果我可以活下来
"I hope I make it through this...
好让我再见彼得派克一面
...so I can see Peter Parker's face one more time."
真的吗
Really?
只有一个人自始至终陪着我
There's only one man who's always been there for me...
让我觉得
...who makes me feel...
我远比自己想像的好很多
...like I'm more than I ever thought I could be.
我就是
That I'm just...
我
...me.
而且感觉很好
And that's okay.
事实是
The truth is...
我爱你
...I love you.
我好爱你  彼得
I love you so much,Peter.
我很想跟她说我有多爱她
All I wanted was to tell her how much I loved her.
但我不能
I can't....
你不能什么
You can't what?
告诉你
Tell you...
一切  我的意思是  太多事情了
...everything.I mean,there's so much to tell.
对啊  有太多事要讲了
Yeah.There's so much to tell.
我要你知道
I want you to know...
我会永远陪着你
...that I will always be there for you.
我也会永远照顾你
I will always be there to take care of you.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
我会永远是你的朋友
I will always be your friend.
只是朋友吗
Only a friend...
彼得派克
...Peter Parker?
我只能给你这么多
That's all I have to give.
不管我的未来怎样走
Whatever life holds in store for me...
我永远忘不了这句话
...I will never forget these words.:
能力愈大  责任愈重
"With great power comes great responsibility."
这是我的天赋
This is my gift.
也是我的诅咒
My curse.
我是谁
Who am I?
我是蜘蛛侠
I'm Spider - Man.